<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<assessment-results 
    uuid="4918e6c8-bc41-43ef-b038-f343f0a8d5e2"
    xmlns="http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/1.0">
    <metadata>
        <title>GoodRead Pre-Authorization Assessment Report</title>
        <last-modified>2023-05-19T09:53:00-04:00</last-modified>
        <version>0.9</version>
        <oscal-version>1.0.4</oscal-version>
        <role id="assessor">
            <title>IFA Security Control Assessor</title>
        </role>
        <party uuid="e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58" type="person">
            <name>Amy Assessor</name>
            <member-of-organization>3a675986-b4ff-4030-b178-e953c2e55d64</member-of-organization>
        </party>
        <party uuid="3a675986-b4ff-4030-b178-e953c2e55d64" type="organization">
            <name>Important Federal Agency</name>
            <short-name>IFA</short-name>
            <link href="https://www.ifa.gov" rel="website"/>
        </party>
        <responsible-party role-id="assessor">
            <party-uuid>e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58</party-uuid>
        </responsible-party>
    </metadata>
    <import-ap href="./ap.oscal.xml"/>
    <local-definitions>
        <activity uuid="52277182-1ba3-4cb6-8d96-b1b97aaf9d6b">
            <title>Examine System Elements for Least Privilege Design and Implementation</title>
            <description>
                <p>The activity and it steps will be performed by the assessor and facilitated by owner, ISSO, and product team for the IFA GoodRead system with necessary information and access about least privilege design and implementation of the system's elements: the application, web framework, server, and cloud account infrastructure.</p>
            </description>
            <prop name="method" value="EXAMINE"/>
            <step uuid="733e3cbf-e398-46b6-9c02-a2cb534c341e">
                <title>Obtain Network Access via VPN to IFA GoodRead Environment</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will obtain network access with appropriately configured VPN account to see admin frontend to the application for PAO staff, which is only accessible via VPN with an appropriately configured role for PAO staff accounts.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>IFA GoodRead Product Team coordinated with ISSO and IFA Office of Information Technology for assessor's account and VPN client to have access to application.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="4ce7e0b4-d69e-4b80-a700-8600b4d4d933">
                <title>Obtain Credentials and Access to AwesomeCloud Account for IFA GoodRead System</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will obtain access to the GoodRead Product Team's AwesomeCloud account with their single sign-on credentials to a read-only assessor role.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>IFA GoodRead Product Team coordinated with ISSO and IFA Office of Information Technology for assessor's single sign-on credentials to have access to a read-only assessor role to the AwesomeCloud account for the IFA GoodRead system.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="3d0297de-e47b-4360-b9c3-cf5c425f86cd">
                <title>Obtain Applcation Access Provided by Product Team</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will obtain non-privileged account credentials with the PAO staff role to test this role in the application does not permit excessive administrative operations.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>IFA GoodRead Product Team has configured the application account and credentials sent via encrypted email to assessor.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="64ca1ef6-3ad4-4747-97c6-40890222463f">
                <title>Confirm Load Balancer Blocks Access to Admin Frontend from Internet</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will confirm that the load balancer for public access does not allow access to Admin Frontend of the application from the Internet.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <step uuid="715f0592-166f-44f6-bb66-d99623e035dc">
                <title>Confirm GoodRead's PAO Role Cannot Manage Users</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will confirm that user's logged into the GoodRead Application with the PAO staff role cannot add, modify, or disable users from the system.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <step uuid="4641957b-a0fa-4c61-af1a-d3e9101efe40">
                <title>Confirm Django Admin Panel Not Available</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will confirm with web-based interface and API methods users with the PAO Staff role cannot access the Django admin panel functions and interactively change application's database records.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <related-controls>
                <control-selection>
                    <include-control control-id="ac-6.1"/>
                </control-selection>
            </related-controls>
            <responsible-role role-id="assessor">
                <party-uuid>e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58</party-uuid>
            </responsible-role>
        </activity>
    </local-definitions>
    <result uuid="e621a431-8eba-4ac7-90cd-ef96e5d90884">
        <title>IFA GoodRead Pre-Authorization Assessment Result 1</title>
        <description>
            <p>This will be the first result once the assessor has completed their final analysis in the assessment.</p>
        </description>
        <start>2023-05-19T10:49:20-04:00</start>
        <reviewed-controls>
            <control-selection>
                <include-control control-id="ac-6.1"/>
            </control-selection>
        </reviewed-controls>
    </result>
</assessment-results>