<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<assessment-results 
    uuid="ed38ade8-9b1d-4c03-a296-c842baf09add"
    xmlns="http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/1.0">
    <metadata>
        <title>GoodRead Pre-Authorization Assessment Report</title>
        <last-modified>2023-05-19T10:53:24-04:00</last-modified>
        <version>1.0</version>
        <oscal-version>1.0.4</oscal-version>
        <role id="assessor">
            <title>IFA Security Control Assessor</title>
        </role>
        <party uuid="e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58" type="person">
            <name>Amy Assessor</name>
            <member-of-organization>3a675986-b4ff-4030-b178-e953c2e55d64</member-of-organization>
        </party>
        <party uuid="3a675986-b4ff-4030-b178-e953c2e55d64" type="organization">
            <name>Important Federal Agency</name>
            <short-name>IFA</short-name>
            <link href="https://www.ifa.gov" rel="website"/>
        </party>
        <responsible-party role-id="assessor">
            <party-uuid>e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58</party-uuid>
        </responsible-party>
    </metadata>
    <import-ap href="./ap.oscal.xml"/>
    <local-definitions>
        <activity uuid="52277182-1ba3-4cb6-8d96-b1b97aaf9d6b">
            <title>Examine System Elements for Least Privilege Design and Implementation</title>
            <description>
                <p>The activity and it steps will be performed by the assessor and facilitated by owner, ISSO, and product team for the IFA GoodRead system with necessary information and access about least privilege design and implementation of the system's elements: the application, web framework, server, and cloud account infrastructure.</p>
            </description>
            <prop name="method" value="EXAMINE"/>
            <step uuid="733e3cbf-e398-46b6-9c02-a2cb534c341e">
                <title>Obtain Network Access via VPN to IFA GoodRead Environment</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will obtain network access with appropriately configured VPN account to see admin frontend to the application for PAO staff, which is only accessible via VPN with an appropriately configured role for PAO staff accounts.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>IFA GoodRead Product Team coordinated with ISSO and IFA Office of Information Technology for assessor's account and VPN client to have access to application.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="4ce7e0b4-d69e-4b80-a700-8600b4d4d933">
                <title>Obtain Credentials and Access to AwesomeCloud Account for IFA GoodRead System</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will obtain access to the GoodRead Product Team's AwesomeCloud account with their single sign-on credentials to a read-only assessor role.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>IFA GoodRead Product Team coordinated with ISSO and IFA Office of Information Technology for assessor's single sign-on credentials to have access to a read-only assessor role to the AwesomeCloud account for the IFA GoodRead system.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="3d0297de-e47b-4360-b9c3-cf5c425f86cd">
                <title>Obtain Applcation Access Provided by Product Team</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will obtain non-privileged account credentials with the PAO staff role to test this role in the application does not permit excessive administrative operations.</p>
                </description>
                <remarks>
                    <p>This step is complete.</p>
                    <p>IFA GoodRead Product Team has configured the application account and credentials sent via encrypted email to assessor.</p>
                </remarks>
            </step>
            <step uuid="64ca1ef6-3ad4-4747-97c6-40890222463f">
                <title>Confirm Load Balancer Blocks Access to Admin Frontend from Internet</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will confirm that the load balancer for public access does not allow access to Admin Frontend of the application from the Internet.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <step uuid="715f0592-166f-44f6-bb66-d99623e035dc">
                <title>Confirm GoodRead's PAO Role Cannot Manage Users</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will confirm that user's logged into the GoodRead Application with the PAO staff role cannot add, modify, or disable users from the system.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <step uuid="4641957b-a0fa-4c61-af1a-d3e9101efe40">
                <title>Confirm Django Admin Panel Not Available</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The assessor will confirm with web-based interface and API methods users with the PAO Staff role cannot access the Django admin panel functions and interactively change application's database records.</p>
                </description>
            </step>
            <related-controls>
                <control-selection>
                    <include-control control-id="ac-6.1"/>
                </control-selection>
            </related-controls>
            <responsible-role role-id="assessor">
                <party-uuid>e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58</party-uuid>
            </responsible-role>
        </activity>
    </local-definitions>
    <result uuid="fc2a3fda-bb39-4d83-9d39-f2d0e6f0af64">
        <title>IFA GoodRead Pre-Authorization Assessment Result 1</title>
        <description>
            <p>This will be the first result once the assessor has completed their final analysis in the assessment.</p>
        </description>
        <start>2023-05-19T10:49:20-04:00</start>
        <end> 2023-05-19T14:35:20-04:00</end>
        <local-definitions>
            <assessment-task uuid="061b6942-f0d4-439c-9d74-92e779992845" type="action">
                <title>Examine System Elements for Least Privilege Design and Implementation</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The activity and it steps will be performed by the assessor and facilitated by owner, ISSO, and product team for the IFA GoodRead system with necessary information and access about least privilege design and implementation of the system's elements: the application, web framework, server, and cloud account infrastructure.</p>
                </description>
                <associated-activity activity-uuid="52277182-1ba3-4cb6-8d96-b1b97aaf9d6b">
                    <subject type="inventory-item">
                        <include-subject subject-uuid="d9550535-40b9-4d8b-861c-07aa8786bf43" type="inventory-item"/>
                    </subject>
                </associated-activity>
                <associated-activity activity-uuid="52277182-1ba3-4cb6-8d96-b1b97aaf9d6b">
                    <subject type="inventory-item">
                        <include-subject subject-uuid="4392599a-9117-416a-87d1-24c7d1b2dd0b" type="inventory-item"/>
                    </subject>
                </associated-activity>
                <associated-activity activity-uuid="52277182-1ba3-4cb6-8d96-b1b97aaf9d6b">
                    <subject type="inventory-item">
                        <include-subject subject-uuid="d911b560-f564-4715-8d2a-76f86127ac73" type="inventory-item"/>
                    </subject>
                </associated-activity>
            </assessment-task>
        </local-definitions>
        <reviewed-controls>
            <control-selection>
                <include-control control-id="ac-6.1"/>
            </control-selection>
        </reviewed-controls>
        <observation uuid="43bb3ecb-f0d2-484a-a24b-6388b111559f">
            <title>AwesomeCloud IAM Roles Examination</title>
            <description>
                <p>Examine AwesomeCloud IAM Roles for least privilege design and implementation.</p>
            </description>
            <method>EXAMINE</method>
            <type>control-objective</type>
            <subject subject-uuid="551b9706-d6a4-4d25-8207-f2ccec548b89" type="component"/>
            <collected>2023-05-19T11:05:48-04:00</collected>
            <remarks>
                <p>The assessor reviewed the AwesomeCloud IAM role for the GoodRead developer. They confirmed users with the developer role are unable to modify any Awesome Load Balancer instance configurations.</p>
            </remarks>
        </observation>
        <observation uuid="0c4de4fc-9bde-46af-b6fe-3b5e78194dcf">
            <title>Django Framework Examination</title>
            <description>
                <p>Examine Django Framework for least privilege design and implementation.</p>
            </description>
            <method>EXAMINE</method>
            <type>control-objective</type>
            <subject subject-uuid="551b9706-d6a4-4d25-8207-f2ccec548b89" type="component"/>
            <collected>2023-05-19T12:14:16-04:00</collected>
            <remarks>
                <p>The assessor attempted to access the admin panel while logged into the GoodRead application as a PAO staff user. They were able to see the admin panel and directly edit database records for the application using the Django Framework's admin panel.</p>
            </remarks>
        </observation>
        <observation uuid="deeb782b-1a22-4b2d-8ef1-f37fe11caabe">
            <title>Examine GoodRead Application User Roles</title>
            <description>
                <p>Examine the custom application roles for GoodRead users for least privilege design and implementation.</p>
            </description>
            <method>EXAMINE</method>
            <type>control-objective</type>
            <subject subject-uuid="551b9706-d6a4-4d25-8207-f2ccec548b89" type="component"/>
            <collected>2023-05-19T12:15:54-04:00</collected>
            <remarks>
                <p>The assessor attempted to create, modify, or disable another PAO staff user while logged into the GoodRead application as a PAO staff user by attempting API calls their current session cookie. They were unable to create, modify, or disable any other users and were logged out of the application.</p>
            </remarks>
        </observation>
        <risk uuid="8b8bae66-b28c-4fa5-9a20-b79e7322fc00">
            <title>PAO Staff Have Over-Privileged Access to GoodRead System</title>
            <description>
                <p>A user with the privileges of a PAO staff user can exceed the intended privileges for their related business function and directly edit the database for the GoodRead application.</p>
            </description>
            <statement>
                <p>An account without proper least privilege design and implementation can be used to significantly damage links created by the tool for use by public citizens, potentially causing a national outage. If an outage were to occur, IFA and Government policy will require the CIO of the agency to notify the Department of Homeland Security and the public.</p>
                <p>Such an event will cause significant financial and reputational risk to IFA's Administrator, executive staff, and the agency overall.</p>
            </statement>
            <status>investigating</status>
        </risk>
        <finding uuid="74155124-9b75-4bbd-b78f-ba3d8c2532b5">
            <title>Django Framework Admin Panel Not Disabled</title>
            <description>
                <p>The assessor was able to access and modify database records as a user with the low privilege PAO Staff role, not the role of a developer. Additionally, the SSP documents that this functionality with the admin panel, implying the default <code>is_staff</code> role and attribute is disabled, which is contrary to the assessor's observation.</p>
            </description>
            <target type="objective-id" target-id="ac-6.1_obj">
                <description>
                    <p>This is a finding.</p>
                </description>
                <status state="not-satisfied"></status>
            </target>
            <implementation-statement-uuid>d5f9b263-965d-440b-99e7-77f5df670a11</implementation-statement-uuid>
            <related-observation observation-uuid="0c4de4fc-9bde-46af-b6fe-3b5e78194dcf"/>
            <associated-risk risk-uuid="8b8bae66-b28c-4fa5-9a20-b79e7322fc00" />
        </finding>
    </result>
</assessment-results>