<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<plan-of-action-and-milestones
    uuid="1906ca41-9086-4838-a5f0-a3661462b91e"
    xmlns="http://csrc.nist.gov/ns/oscal/1.0">
    <metadata>
        <title>IFA GoodRead Plan of Action and Milestones</title>
        <last-modified>2023-05-19T12:57:08.000-04:00</last-modified>
        <version>20230519</version>
        <oscal-version>1.0.4</oscal-version>
    </metadata>
    <import-ssp href="../3-implementation/ssp.oscal.xml"/>
    <system-id identifier-type="http://ietf.org/rfc/rfc4122">8101e04d-8305-4e73-bb95-6b59f645b143</system-id>
    <observation uuid="0c4de4fc-9bde-46af-b6fe-3b5e78194dcf">
        <title>Django Framework Examination</title>
        <description>
            <p>Examine Django Framework for least privilege design and implementation.</p>
        </description>
        <method>EXAMINE</method>
        <type>control-objective</type>
        <subject subject-uuid="551b9706-d6a4-4d25-8207-f2ccec548b89" type="component"/>
        <collected>2023-05-19T12:14:16-04:00</collected>
        <remarks>
            <p>The assessor attempted to access the admin panel while logged into the GoodRead application as a PAO staff user. They were able to see the admin panel and directly edit database records for the application using the Django Framework's admin panel.</p>
        </remarks>
    </observation>
    <risk uuid="8b8bae66-b28c-4fa5-9a20-b79e7322fc00">
        <title>IFA-GOODREAD-RISK-1: PAO Staff Have Over-Privileged Access to GoodRead System</title>
        <description>
            <p>A user with the privileges of a PAO staff user can exceed the intended privileges for their related business function and directly edit the database for the GoodRead application.</p>
        </description>
        <statement>
            <p>An account without proper least privilege design and implementation can be used to significantly damage links created by the tool for use by public citizens, potentially causing a national outage. If an outage were to occur, IFA and Government policy will require the CIO of the agency to notify the Department of Homeland Security and the public.</p>
            <p>Such an event will cause significant financial and reputational risk to IFA's Administrator, executive staff, and the agency overall.</p>
        </statement>
        <status>deviation-approved</status>
        <characterization>
            <origin>
                <actor type="party" actor-uuid="e7730080-71ce-4b20-bec4-84f33136fd58"/>
            </origin>
            <facet name="likelihood" value="low" system="https://ifa.gov/division/ociso/sca"/>
            <facet name="impact" value="high" system="https://ifa.gov/division/ociso/sca"/>
        </characterization>
        <mitigating-factor uuid="401c15c9-ad6b-4d4a-a591-7d53a3abb3b6">
            <description>
                <p>The GoodRead application is designed and implemented to only allow access to the administrative functions for those with PAO staff fole via the VPN via network configuration between the IFA Enterprise Support Systems and the GoodRead AwesomeCloud account. Additionally, the load balanacer configuration only allows access to view shortlinks from the public internet.</p>
            </description>
        </mitigating-factor>
        <deadline>2024-01-01T05:00:00-04:00</deadline>
        <response uuid="d28873f7-0a45-476d-9cd3-1d2ec0b8bca1" lifecycle="planned">
            <title>IFA-GOODREAD-RISK1-RESPONSE: IFA GoodRead Prouct Team Response</title>
            <description>
                <p>The GoodRead Product Team does not have sufficient personnel and budget to implement the required changes in their use of the Django Framework and its configuration in this quarter. With the consultation of the ISSO and the assessor, the owner of the GoodRead system has decided to accept this risk until the end of December 2023. From September to December, budget will be available for the Good Read Product Team's developer and system engineer to completely disable the functionality that is the source of the risk and its originating finding.</p>
            </description>
            <prop name="type" value="accept"/>
            <task uuid="f8b1d4cb-d1a9-4932-9859-2e93b325f287" type="milestone">
                <title>End of Year Project Management Report of Developed Remediations</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The owner, ISSO, and product team of the GoodRead Project intend to complete the necessary development between September 2023 and December 2023. Whether or not the necessary development for remedation is complete, the product team's project manager will submit the final annual report. They will identify this work item and whether it has been completed.</p>
                </description>
                <timing>
                    <within-date-range start="2023-09-29T09:00:00-04:00" end="2024-01-01T05:00:00-04:00"/>
                </timing>
            </task>
        </response>
        <related-observation observation-uuid="0c4de4fc-9bde-46af-b6fe-3b5e78194dcf"/>
    </risk>
    <poam-item uuid="e174dfb9-0ae3-4a8f-8e7c-081527b84337">
        <title>Update Django Framework Configuration to Disable Default Admin Panel</title>
        <description>
            <p>Budget and technical staff are needed to re-design and re-implement a part of the GoodRead application's use of a web appplication programming framework to mitigate the risk of low privilege users directly modifying the database of this application. This application is a high-visibility service and integral to future operations of the IFA Office of Public Affairs and its staff.</p>
        </description>
        <related-observation observation-uuid="0c4de4fc-9bde-46af-b6fe-3b5e78194dcf"/>
        <associated-risk risk-uuid="401c15c9-ad6b-4d4a-a591-7d53a3abb3b6" />
    </poam-item>
</plan-of-action-and-milestones>